findanewhome.com 2019-06-12

# Zoopla’s Privacy Policy

This service is operated by Zoopla Limited. If you visit our website, use our apps or contact us, this policy is for you. It’s about how we protect your data and respect your privacy.

This policy was last updated in **May 2019**. We update it from time to time as we make improvements or when laws change. Please check it every now and then to make sure you know exactly how we use your data.

Zoopla

Our responsibility

We are the ‘controller’ of your personal data. This means we decide how and why your data is processed any time you use our products. We go into this in more detail below.

You

Your responsibility

You should read this policy and make sure you’re happy with it before using our services. If anything is unclear, or you disagree with something, please [contact us](https://www.zoopla.co.uk/contact).

## Your property information on Zoopla

This policy applies to how we use your personal data. It does not apply to information about properties shown on our websites and apps.

If you have questions about property information, please [contact our customer care team](https://www.zoopla.co.uk/contact). If you are selling or letting a property which is being advertised on our websites and apps, please direct any questions to your agent.

## Data we collect about you

When you use our services, we collect data. Sometimes you might give us data, like your email address. Sometimes data about you is collected automatically, like which pages on our website you’ve visited. This section explains the types of information we collect about you when you use our services, why we collect it and the legal basis on which we use it.

### Information about you

#### Your contact details

e.g. Your email address or phone number.

Zoopla

What’s in it for us?

We use this information to distinguish you from other users and to contact you if we need to. If you sign up to property alerts or marketing emails, we’ll send them to your email address. If you send a message to an agent or developer through Zoopla, we’ll share your contact details with them.

You

What’s in it for you?

You can contact us about our services and get the property alerts and marketing emails that you want. Also, if you sent a message to an agent or developer through Zoopla, they can reply to you directly.

We’re allowed to use your data if it’s necessary for our (or someone else’s) ‘legitimate interests’ and those interests aren’t outweighed by your rights. Our legitimate interests are:

  * providing and improving our services
  * enabling you to save properties, searches, claim your home and carry out other tasks using your Zoopla account
  * personalising your experience of our services
  * learning from the way you use our services
  * making sure our services are secure

What’s this? Got it

#### Your account information

e.g. Your login details and preferences.

Zoopla

What’s in it for us?

We use this information to maintain your account and save your preferences.

You

What’s in it for you?

Adding details to your account means we can give you a much more personalised experience when it comes to services, property searches and your interests.

We’re allowed to use your data if it’s necessary for our (or someone else’s) ‘legitimate interests’ and those interests aren’t outweighed by your rights. Our legitimate interests are:

  * providing and improving our services
  * enabling you to save properties, searches, claim your home and carry out other tasks using your Zoopla account
  * personalising your experience of our services
  * learning from the way you use our services
  * making sure our services are secure

What’s this? Got it

#### Marketing preferences

e.g. Your marketing email subscription preferences.

Zoopla

What’s in it for us?

We get to remind you of all the ways Zoopla can help and hopefully encourage you to use us more often. We also get paid by some trusted businesses to send marketing emails on their behalf. We don’t give your contact details to those other businesses.

You

What’s in it for you?

Zoopla is free to use. With your permission, we’ll send you instant alerts about properties that match your search criteria. We can also send you emails about products and services which we think will interest you, including some offered by other businesses we trust.

‘Consent’ is when you give us your permission to use your data for a specific purpose. You can withdraw your consent at any time. Simply update your marketing preferences in your account, click ‘unsubscribe’ in any email we send you, or [contact us](https://www.zoopla.co.uk/contact).

What’s this? Got it

### Information about what you do

#### Online behaviour

e.g. Information about how you got to, and use, our websites and apps.

Zoopla

What’s in it for us?

Understanding how you use our website and apps helps us to improve them. Also, some trusted businesses pay us to advertise on Zoopla. We use our understanding of the way you behave on Zoopla, and elsewhere on the internet, to show ads we think will interest you.

You

What’s in it for you?

Zoopla is free to use. Plus, we get better and better at delivering what you need and meeting your expectations. We can make the information you see more relevant and personalised to you. Any ads we show will be more tailored to you too.

We’re allowed to use your data if it’s necessary for our (or someone else’s) ‘legitimate interests’ and those interests aren’t outweighed by your rights. Our legitimate interests are:

  * providing and improving our services
  * enabling you to save properties, searches, claim your home and carry out other tasks using your Zoopla account
  * personalising your experience of our services
  * learning from the way you use our services
  * making sure our services are secure

Sometimes we gather this information using cookies and other similar technologies. We sometimes need your consent to do this. You can find out more about this and how to manage this consent in our [cookie policy](https://www.zoopla.co.uk/privacy/cookies/).

What’s this? Got it

#### Search information

e.g. Information about your property searches.

Zoopla

What’s in it for us?

We use this information to understand what you’re looking for and make informed suggestions. We can also give agents and developers who use Zoopla a clearer idea of the kind of property that we think would interest you.

You

What’s in it for you?

We use this information to make your experience on our websites and apps better. Your property search results will be more relevant and useful. Sometimes we might suggest properties we’re confident you’ll like, even if they don’t exactly match your search criteria. You’ll also get a faster and more useful service from agents and developers who use our websites and apps.

We’re allowed to use your data if it’s necessary for our (or someone else’s) ‘legitimate interests’ and those interests aren’t outweighed by your rights. Our legitimate interests are:

  * providing and improving our services
  * enabling you to save properties, searches, claim your home and carry out other tasks using your Zoopla account
  * personalising your experience of our services
  * learning from the way you use our services
  * making sure our services are secure

Sometimes we gather this information using cookies and other similar technologies. We sometimes need your consent to do this. You can find out more about this and how to manage this consent in our [cookie policy](https://www.zoopla.co.uk/privacy/cookies/).

What’s this? Got it

### Your communications

#### Enquiries to agents and developers

e.g. Your contact details and messages you send to agents and developers through our websites and apps.

Zoopla

What’s in it for us?

We use this information to send your message to agents and developers. We also analyse the enquiries that are being sent to improve our service.

You

What’s in it for you?

You are quickly connected to agents and developers to talk about your enquiry. The tools and features available to you from Zoopla get more useful and valuable.

We’re allowed to use your data if it’s necessary for our (or someone else’s) ‘legitimate interests’ and those interests aren’t outweighed by your rights. Our legitimate interests are:

  * providing and improving our services
  * enabling you to save properties, searches, claim your home and carry out other tasks using your Zoopla account
  * personalising your experience of our services
  * learning from the way you use our services
  * making sure our services are secure

What’s this? Got it

#### Surveys and responses

e.g. Feedback tools on our websites, apps and emails.

Zoopla

What’s in it for us?

We use your opinion about our services to measure how we’re doing and make improvements.

You

What’s in it for you?

You get to tell us when you think our services are great or how they could be better for you.

We’re allowed to use your data if it’s necessary for our (or someone else’s) ‘legitimate interests’ and those interests aren’t outweighed by your rights. Our legitimate interests are:

  * providing and improving our services
  * enabling you to save properties, searches, claim your home and carry out other tasks using your Zoopla account
  * personalising your experience of our services
  * learning from the way you use our services
  * making sure our services are secure

What’s this? Got it

#### Telephone calls

e.g. Recordings of your calls with us and with agents and developers using the phone numbers shown on our websites and apps.

Zoopla

What’s in it for us?

We use call recordings to make sure you’re getting a great service from our team and our members. We can investigate when something has gone wrong, like if an agent or developer has broken our rules. We use call recordings to train our team and our members and make your call recording available to the agent or developer you contacted. This helps them to improve their service as well.

You

What’s in it for you?

You get a better quality service from Zoopla and our members. Also, any complaints can be resolved more quickly.

‘Consent’ is when you give us your permission to use your data for a specific purpose.

You can withdraw your consent at any time. Simply [contact us](https://www.zoopla.co.uk/contact).

If you do not consent to us recording your telephone call to us, please [contact us online instead](https://www.zoopla.co.uk/contact).

If you do not consent to us recording your telephone call to an agent or developer, then please do not use the telephone numbers on our websites or apps. You’ll be able to find another number on the agent’s or developer’s own website.

What’s this? Got it

## Your rights

You have personal data rights. They fall into six categories.

  * Erasure

You can ask us to erase your information in some circumstances. [Find out more](https://ico.org.uk/your-data-matters/your-right-to-get-your-data-deleted/)

  * Rectification

You can ask us to correct inaccurate or incomplete information. [Find out more](https://ico.org.uk/your-data-matters/your-right-to-get-your-data-corrected/)

  * Access

You can ask us for copies of your information. This right always applies but there are some exceptions, so you might not get everything we process. [Find out more](https://ico.org.uk/your-data-matters/your-right-of-access/)

  * Restrict processing

You can ask us to restrict processing your information in some circumstances. [Find out more](https://ico.org.uk/your-data-matters/your-right-to-limit-how-organisations-use-your-data/)

  * Data portability

This applies to information you give us. You can ask us to transfer this information to another organisation or give it to you. This only applies if we are processing based on your consent or in relation to a contract and that processing is automated. [Find out more](https://ico.org.uk/your-data-matters/your-right-to-data-portability/)

  * Object to processing

You can object to how we process your personal data even if we believe it’s in our or someone else’s legitimate interests. [Find out more](https://ico.org.uk/your-data-matters/the-right-to-object-to-the-use-of-your-data/)

### Your data choices

  1. 1.

**You can choose not to give us your data.** If you do this, you can still browse our websites and use our apps, but you won’t be able to send enquiries, sign up to our emails or register with us.

  2. 2.

**You can turn off cookies.** You can block cookies by adjusting your browser settings or visiting our websites in ‘incognito’ or ‘private’ mode. You can also delete cookies in your browser settings. If you do this, you might not be able to use all our services. [Find out more about cookies](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/).

  3. 3.

**You can tell us not to use your data for marketing.** We’ll always ask for your consent before using your data for marketing. You can say no or withdraw consent at any time. Simply update your marketing preferences in your account, tap ‘unsubscribe’ in any email we send you, or [contact us](https://www.zoopla.co.uk/contact).

## How we store your data

##### Where do we store your data?

The personal data we collect is processed at our offices in the UK and in data processing facilities that are provided to us by third parties.

Some of these third parties are located outside the UK and the European Economic Area (EEA). If we ever transfer your personal data outside the UK and the EEA, we take steps to protect your privacy and make sure that the transfers comply with the law.

##### How long do we store your data for?

We only keep your data long enough to carry out the task it was collected for. The amount of time varies depending on the type of data and how we use it.

##### Do any third parties process your data?

Like many technology businesses, we use trusted suppliers to host our services (including our websites and apps) and power our business systems. We only choose partners who have appropriate security measures in place to keep your data safe.

We only share your personal data with these suppliers when we absolutely need to. If these suppliers are outside the UK and the EEA, we take steps to protect your privacy and make sure that those transfers comply with the law.

## Cookies

Our websites and apps use ‘cookies’ and other similar technologies. A cookie is a piece of information placed on your device so we can remember something about you or your device.

Cookies help us monitor and improve our services, and to personalise your experience (including the ads you see on our websites, our apps and elsewhere). You can find out more in our [cookie policy](https://www.zoopla.co.uk/privacy/cookies/).

## Links to third party websites

Our websites and apps contain links to other websites. This policy does not apply to those other websites. You should check the privacy policy of any other website before submitting your personal data to it.

## How to contact us

We hope all of the above makes sense and you're happy with how we use your personal data. If not, please contact us using any of the following methods.

Our Data Protection Officer (DPO) is Michael Haynes. You can contact him at [dpo@zpg.co.uk](mailto:dpo@zpg.co.uk).

You can complain about how we use your personal data at any time to the Information Commissioner’s Office. [Find out more](https://ico.org.uk/make-a-complaint/)
